Khamzaev Daler

Senior Android Engineer

dalerhamzaev@gmail.com +992 55 835 00 44 LinkedIn: <u>daler</u> Dushanbe, Tajikistan Website: <u>dalerdeveloper</u> Moscow, Russia

I am professional Senior Android Engineer with a lot of experience in Android, iOS and Multiplatform development with about 5 years' experience. My main goal is to evolve as an engineer and grow my expertise! I'm intended to relocate.

Hard Skills

- Swift, Kotlin, Java
- KMM, Compose, Android Jetpack, Kotlin Coroutines, RxSwift, RxJava, RxKotlin, SwiftUI, SQLDelight, Room, Koin, Dagger2, Hilt, Ktor, Bluetooth, Sockets.
- MVI, MVVM
- Firebase
- SOLID, KISS
- XCode, Android Studio, Git
- Gitlab CI/CD

Soft Skills

- Communication
- Team work
- Problem-solving
- Critical thinning
- Time management

Experience

Exante (05/2022 - Present) – Senior Android Engineer (Remote):

- Refactoring main page app, that's increased application performance. Removed all old legacy and remade main logic
 of update information on main page. Loading of main page became faster in 2 times.
- Support main code base and helped in code review, that helped increase value of code.

Luxoft (06/2021 - 05/2022) - Senior Android Engineer (Moscow, Russia):

- Refactoring whole application to new tech stack, that helped to improve UI, UX experience
- Implementation database solution, that increased performance of the whole application, that helped us to use smaller ram of user mobiles phones.

Sputnic (02/2019 - 06/2021) - Middle Android Engineer (Moscow, Russia):

- Developing analog of Play market, that helped us to update and release products to users. This app I made from scratch.
- Refactoring main page of the browser that improved user experience, through removing old legacy and inject new frameworks like Retrofit

Space1s (09/2018 - 06/2021) - Middle Android Engineer (Moscow, Russia):

- Develop application to control robots, that worked on Arduino, this solution helped to control them through Sockets and Bluetooth.
- Develop application that helped courier to accept payments from bank cards through mobile phones. Now couriers
 can easily accept payment, when they delivered goods for clients.

Education

Applied computer science in business Moscow State University of Transport (MIIT) Bachelor of Technology – Btech

Projects

Telekarta App for iOS and Android

This app is Personal cabinet, where clients can change their subscriptions, contact to support, look tv programs, update personal info and check contract info. This full REST API app.

- Developing Android and iOS apps from scratch using KMM, Compose, Ktor, SwiftUI, MVI, Firebase
- Publishing all apps to Google Play and App Store

Game Three in Row

This is my personal game with a lot of animations, where you can build diamonds in one row or column.

- Designed and developed whole game using LibGdx, Koltin, Coroutines, Firebase
- Developing model generator for the whole app, like diamonds generation, back game animation.

Sitilink App for payments

This app works with INGENICO terminals though Bluetooth and Sockets.

Designed and developed app for payments via INGENICO terminals